I'm here to share my photography.
جئت هنا لأشارككم صوري
Or is it photography?
هل هي فعلا صور؟
Because, of course, this is a photograph
فبالتأكيد صورة كهذه
that you can't take with your camera.
لا يمكن التقاطها بآلة تصوير
Yet, my interest in photography started
اهتمامي بالتصوير بدأ
as I got my first digital camera
منذ حصولي على كاميرا رقمية
at the age of 15.
في سن الـ 15
It mixed with my earlier passion for drawing,
واختلط مع ولعي المبكر بالرسم
but it was a bit different,
لكنه كان مختلفا قليلا
because using the camera,
فعند استخدام الكاميرا
the process was in the planning instead.
يكون التخطيط هو الأساس
And when you take a photograph with a camera,
وحين تلتقط صورة بالكاميرا
the process ends when you press the trigger.
تنتهي العملية بضغط الزر
So to me it felt like photography was more about
لذلك بالنسبة لي التصوير كان يعتمد أكثر
being at the right place and the right time.
على التواجد في المكان المناسب في الوقت المناسب
I felt like anyone could do that.
وشعرت أنه بإمكان أي شخص القيام بذلك
So I wanted to create something different,
لذا أردت ابتكار ما هو مختلف
something where the process starts
يتم ببدء العملية
when you press the trigger.
حين تضغط على الزر
Photos like this:
صورة مثل هذه:
construction going on along a busy road.
بناء يتم في طريق مزدحمة
But it has an unexpected twist.
لكن بها تحريف غير متوقع
And despite that,
وبرغم ذلك
it retains a level of realism.
تحافظ على مستوى من الواقعية
Or photos like these --
أو صور مثل هذه
both dark and colorful,
مظلمة وملونة
but all with a common goal
لكن هدفها واحد
of retaining the level of realism.
وهو الحفاظ على مستوى من الواقعية
When I say realism,
حين أقول واقعية
I mean photo-realism.
أقصد واقعية الصورة
Because, of course,
لأنها بالطبع
it's not something you can capture really,
ليست بالشيء الذي يمكن التقاطه في الواقع
but I always want it to look like it could have been captured somehow
لكنني دائما أريدها أن تبدو وكأنها التقطت
as a photograph.
كصورة
Photos where you will need a brief moment to think
صور تدفعك للتفكير للحظة
to figure out the trick.
لاكتشاف الحيلة
So it's more about capturing an idea
فالأمر يتعلق بالتقاط فكرة
than about capturing a moment really.
أكثر من التقاط لحظة حقيقة
But what's the trick
لكن ما هي الحيلة
that makes it look realistic?
التي تجعله يبدو واقعيا؟
Is it something about the details
هل لذلك علاقة بالتفاصيل
or the colors?
أو الألوان؟
Is it something about the light?
أو بالإضاءة؟
What creates the illusion?
ما الذي يخلق الوهم؟
Sometimes the perspective is the illusion.
أحيانا ما يكون المنظور هو الوهم
But in the end, it comes down to how we interpret the world
لكن في النهاية، يتلخص الأمر في كيفية تفسيرنا للعالم
and how it can be realized on a two-dimensional surface.
وكيف يمكن أن يتحقق على سطح ثنائي الأبعاد
It's not really what is realistic,
لا يتعلق الأمر فقط بما هو واقعي
it's what we think looks realistic really.
لكن بما نظن أنه يبدو واقعيا
So I think the basics
وبالتالي أعتقد أن الأسس
are quite simple.
بسيطة جدا
I just see it as a puzzle of reality
أراها فقط كلغز للواقع
where you can take different pieces of reality and put it together
حيث يمكن أن تجمع قطعا مختلفة من الواقع معا
to create alternate reality.
لتخلق واقعا بديلا
And let me show you a simple example.
ودعوني أريكم مثالا بسيطا
Here we have three perfectly imaginable physical objects,
لدينا هنا ثلاثة أشياء مادية يمكن تخيلها
something we all can relate to living in a three-dimensional world.
ويمكننا جميعا ربطها بالعالم ثلاثي الأبعاد
But combined in a certain way,
لكنها مجمعة بطريقة معينة
they can create something that still looks three-dimensional,
لتشكل ما يبدو وكأنه ثلاثي الأبعاد
like it could exist.
وكأنه محتمل الوجود
But at the same time, we know it can't.
لكننا في نفس الوقت نعرف أن ذلك مستحيلا
So we trick our brains,
وبالتالي نخدع عقولنا
because our brain simply doesn't accept the fact
لأنها لا تقبل حقيقة
that it doesn't really make sense.
أن ذلك الشكل لا معنى له
And I see the same process
وأرى نفس العملية
with combining photographs.
في تركيب الصور
It's just really about combining different realities.
يكمن الأمر في الجمع بين أكثر من واقع
So the things that make a photograph look realistic,
فما يجعل صورة تبدو واقعية
I think it's the things that we don't even think about,
هي الأشياء التي لا تخطر ببالنا
the things all around us in our daily lives.
الأشياء الموجودة حولنا في حياتنا اليومية
But when combining photographs,
لكن عند تجميع الصور
this is really important to consider,
علينا التفكير بها
because otherwise it just looks wrong somehow.
وإلا ستبدو غير مقنعة بشكل ما
So I would like to say that there are three simple rules to follow
أود أن أقول أن هناك ثلاث قواعد بسيطة
to achieve a realistic result.
للوصول إلى نتيجة واقعية
As you can see, these images aren't really special.
كما ترون هاتين الصورتين ليستا فريدتين
But combined, they can create something like this.
لكن عند جمعهما نخلق شيئا كهذا
So the first rule is that photos combined
وبالتالي فالقاعدة الأولى هي أن الصور المركبة
should have the same perspective.
يجب أن يجمعها نفس المنظور
Secondly, photos combined
ثانيا، الصور المركبة
should have the same type of light.
يجب أن تتميز بنفس نوع الإضاءة
And these two images both fulfill these two requirements --
الشرطان المتوفران بهاتين الصورتين
shot at the same height and in the same type of light.
تم التقاطهما من نفس الارتفاع وتحت نفس الإضاءة
The third one is about making it impossible to distinguish
القاعدة الثالثة هي استحالة تمييز
where the different images begin and end
الحد الذي تبدأ عنده الصور المختلفة وتنتهي
by making it seamless.
بتحقيق السلاسة
Make it impossible to say
حتى يستحيل أن تكتشف
how the image actually was composed.
كيف تم تركيب الصورة
So by matching color, contrast and brightness
فبمطابقة الألوان والتباين والإضاءة
in the borders between the different images,
في الحدود ما بين الصور المختلفة
adding photographic defects
وإضافة تأثيرات فوتوغرافية
like depth of field,
مثل عمق المجال
desaturated colors and noise,
الألوان غير المشبعة والضجيج
we erase the borders between the different images
نمحو الحدود بين الصور المختلفة
and make it look like one single image,
ونجعلها تبدو كصورة واحدة
despite the fact that one image
على الرغم من أن الصورة الواحدة
can contain hundreds of layers basically.
قد تحتوي أساسا على مئات الطبقات
So here's another example.
وها هو مثال آخر
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
One might think that this is just an image of a landscape
قد يعتقد أحدكم أنها مجرد صورة لمنظر طبيعي
and the lower part is what's manipulated.
وأن الجزء السفلي فقط هو ما تمت معالجته
But this image is actually entirely composed
لكن في الواقع هذه الصورة مركبة بالكامل
of photographs from different locations.
من صور من أماكن مختلفة
I personally think that it's easier to actually create a place
أعتقد شخصيا أن إنشاء مكان أسهل
than to find a place,
من إيجاد مكان
because then you don't need to compromise
لأنه آنذاك لن تلجأ لحل وسط
with the ideas in your head.
فالأفكار في رأسك
But it does require a lot of planning.
لكن ذلك يتطلب الكثير من التخطيط
And getting this idea during winter,
وبمجرد أن خطرت لي هذه الفكرة في الشتاء
I knew that I had several months to plan it,
أدركت أن أمامي عدة أشهر للتخطيط
to find the different locations
لإيجاد الأماكن المختلفة
for the pieces of the puzzle basically.
لتجميع قطع اللغز
So for example,
فعلى سبيل المثال
the fish was captured on a fishing trip.
تم تصوير السمكة في رحلة صيد
The shores are from a different location.
والشواطئ من أماكن مختلفة
The underwater part was captured in a stone pit.
الجزء السفلي تحت الماء التقط من حفرة حجرية
And yeah, I even turned the house on top of the island red
وقد حولت المنزل أعلى الجزيرة إلى الأحمر
to make it look more Swedish.
لأجعلها تميل إلى الطابع السويدي
So to achieve a realistic result,
الحصول على نتيجة واقعية إذن
I think it comes down to planning.
يمكن تلخيصه في التخطيط
It always starts with a sketch, an idea.
فدائما ما يبدأ برسم تخطيطي، بفكرة
Then it's about combining the different photographs.
ومن ثم تجميع الصور المختلفة
And here every piece is very well planned.
وهنا يخطط لكل قطعة بدقة
And if you do a good job capturing the photos,
وإن تمكنت من التقاط الصور بنجاح
the result can be quite beautiful
تحصل على نتائج جميلة جدا
and also quite realistic.
وواقعية جدا أيضا
So all the tools are out there,
فكل الأدوات موجودة حولنا
and the only thing that limits us
ولا يقيدنا سوى
is our imagination.
خيالنا
Thank you.
شكرا لكم
(Applause)
(تصفيق)